Said Mghabghab

Toronto, ON, M1R4H1 | **Phone**: (647) 679-6916 | **Email**: Saidmghabghab@gmail.com **LinkedIn**: https://www.linkedin.com/in/said-mghabghab | **GitHub**: https://github.com/saidmg/

Portfolio: https://portfolio-said.herokuapp.com/

SUMMARY

Trilingual(English, French, Arabic) Full Stack Developer with enhanced communication, team-building, and leadership skills acquired through 10 years of scouting. With a bachelor degree in computer engineering that developed the passion to solve problems, and manage time. Attending a software development internship, working as a web developer, and taking a 24-week intensive full stack program increased my knowledge in technical programming skills such as HTML, CSS, Javascript, NodeJs, MySql, Express, ReactJs and more.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Node.Js, Express, Javascript, jQuery, Git, GitHub, MySQL, SQL, MongoDB, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, APIs, JSON, REST, AJAX, The Command Line, C#, PHP, Python, , Heroku, MERN Stack, Writing Tests, Agile Methodology, MATLAB, Visual Studio, LabView, and C++, Data Structures, Computer Science Fundamentals.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Web Developer May 2019 – Sep 2019

IGEC Sarl. - Lebanon.

- Established and maintained positive relationships with other developers by making sure that everyone's opinion and idea had been taken into consideration.
- Utilized creativity and logical thinking to come up with new solutions to complicated tasks.

Software Developer Intern

Jul 2018 - Aug 2018

SABIS – Lebanon.

• Where I have developed teamwork and time management skills by completing the assigned tasks using the agile scrum methodology

APPLICATIONS BUILT

Goldie Mohr Ltd. | https://github.com/GoldieMohrProject/goldie-mohr | https://goldie-mohr-full.herokuapp.com/

- A new and highly improved web page for the company Goldie Mohr Ltd.
- Full-Stack Developer | Worked initially on the front end as requested by the client and then added backend features for personal skills enhancement.
- Built with Reactjs ,bootstrap , Nodejs, Expressjs, and npm packages such as bcrypt, Emailjs, dotenv, uuid, with the use of eslint and much more.

Panther Chatroom | https://github.com/PurplePanthers/PantherChatroom | https://panther-chatroom.herokuapp.com/

- Live chat to meet new people and make new friends.
- Worked mostly on the backend, where I had to learn about a library that enables real-time, bidirectional and event-based communication between the browser and the server.(socket.io)
- Built with Html, Css, Javascript, Node is, Express is, Socket io with the use of Github and Kanban.

Essential Finance | https://github.com/saidmg/essential-finance | https://saidmg.github.io/essential-finance/

- Targets people who are beginners, intermediate, or experienced with finance and stock.
- Full-Stack Developer | Worked on both backend and frontend while making sure that tasks were fairly assigned and completed using Scrum methodology
- Built with Html, Css, Bootstrap, APIs, Javascript, and Jquery with the use of Github and Kanban.

Team Profile Generator | https://github.com/saidmg/team-profile-generator | walkthrough video

- Takes in information about employees on a software engineering team, then generates an HTML webpage that displays summaries for each person.
- Performed by Node.Js, Inquirer for collecting user's input, and Jest for running the unit tests.

EXTRA WORK EXPERIENCE

Receiver Nov 2019 - Dec 2020

Manufacturer's Warehouse Sale-Toronto

• Enhanced adaptability and cooperation by being responsible for organizing the inventory and providing the requested items for sale while taking care of customer's needs and maintaining their satisfaction.

Cashier Jun 2015 – Sep 2019

Passion Juice – Lebanon

• Improved communication, work ethics, and social skills, not only by handling customers orders, but also by providing help to coworkers by also making cocktails when it gets crowded.

Parking registration and ID distribution

Sep 2016 – Jun 2019 Notre

Dame University Louaize's Student Affairs Office - Lebanon

• Provided attention to details, workplace confidentiality, and efficiency. Which pushed the supervisor toward requesting me every semester until my graduation.

EDUCATION

Certificate, Full stack Web Development

Jan 2021 - Apr 2021

University of toronto - Canada.

Enhanced Language Training Program

Oct 2019 - Dec 2019

Toronto District School Board - Canada.

$\boldsymbol{B.E.}$ in $\boldsymbol{Computer}$ and $\boldsymbol{Communication}$ Engineering - \boldsymbol{ABET} accredited program

2019

Notre Dame University Louaize - Lebanon.

• Undergraduate Thesis: Smart Irrigation System.